# Seokyung An, PhD

## Biostatistician | Epidemiologist

■ seokyung.ann@gmail.com 
 312-209-0231 
 Chicago, United States

https://seokyungan.github.io/

#### Profile

Experienced biostatistician and epidemiologist with a demonstrated history of working in academic research, the National Cancer Center, and currently serving as a Senior Statistical Analyst at Northwestern University. Skilled in biostatistics, data visualization, and clinical research. Strong research professional with a Doctor in Medical Science (PhD) from Seoul National University, specializing in the prediction and prevention of cardiometabolic disease.

#### Education

03/2016 - 08/2022 **Doctor of Philosophy, Medical Science** 

Seoul, South Korea Seoul National University Graduate School, Department of Biomedical Sciences

**Bachelor of Statistics** 03/2012 - 02/2016

Seoul, South Korea Sungshin Women's University, Department of Statistics

#### Skills

Statistical analysis **Artificial intelligence modeling** 

R, SAS, SPSS, PLINK, Python Machine learning and Deep learning

Collaboration **Data management** 

SQL, RedCap Task management and communication

#### Professional Experience

**Senior Statistical Analyst** 07/2023 - present

Chicago, US Northwestern University - The Feinberg School of Medicine

Senior Statistician, Bluhm Cardiovascular Institute

**Postdoctoral fellow** 10/2022 - 06/2023

Ilsan, South Korea National Cancer Center

> Investigated the relationships between environmental and genomic factors in cancer and developed cancer prediction models using artificial intelligence.

03/2016 - 08/2022 Graduate student, full time

Seoul, South Korea Seoul National University Graduate School

Mastered advanced biostatistics and epidemiology and developed metabolic

disease prediction models using artificial intelligence methods.

06/2015 - 08/2015 Intern

Ilsan, Soul Korea National Cancer Center

Investigated the association between colorectal cancer and dietary intake.

06/2014 - 08/2014 Intern

Seoul, South Korea Seoul National University Cancer Research Institute

Investigated hereditary breast cancer and analyzed cohort data from the Korean

Hereditary Breast Cancer Study (KOHBRA).

#### **■** Publications (indicates\* first)

09/2023 Comparison of intravascular ultrasound, optical coherence tomography, and

conventional angiography-guided percutaneous coronary interventions: A systematic review, network meta-analysis, and meta-regression

Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. PMID: 37483068

Park DY\*, **An S**, Jolly N, Attanasio S, Yadav N, Gutierrez JA, Nanna MG, Rao SV, Vij A.

02/2023 Factor Xa Inhibitors Versus Vitamin K Antagonist in Morbidly Obese Patients

With Venous Thromboembolism: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis 🛭

BMC Cardiovasc Disord. PMID: 36814196 Park DY\*, **An S\***, Arif AW, Sana MK, Vij A

02/2023 Trends and impact of intravascular ultrasound and optical coherence

tomography on percutaneous coronary intervention for myocardial

infarction 🛮

Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc. 2023. PMID: 36852085

Park DY\*, Vemmou E\*, **An S**, Nikolakopoulos I, Regan CJ, Cambi BC, Frampton J, Vij

A, Brilakis E, Nanna MG

01/2023 Network Meta-Analysis Comparing Angiotensin Receptor-Neprilysin Inhibitors,

Angiotensin Receptor Blockers, and Angiotensin-Converting Enzyme Inhibitors

in Heart Failure With Reduced Ejection Fraction 🖸

Am J Cardiol. 2023. PMID: 36459752

Park DY\*, **An S**, Attanasio S, Jolly N, Malhotra S, Doukky R, Samsky MD, Sen S,

Ahmad T, Nanna MG, Vij A

11/2022 Indoor tanning and the risk of overall and early-onset melanoma and

non-melanoma skin cancer: Systematic review and meta-analysis. 🛽

Cancers (Basel). PMID: 34885049

**An S\***, Kim K, Moon S, Ko KP, Kim I, Lee JE, Park SK.

11/2022 Abbreviated versus Standard Duration of DAPT after PCI: A Systematic Review

and Network Meta-analysis. Am J Cardiovasc Drugs 🛭

Am J Cardiovasc Drugs. PMID: 35781867

Park DY\*, **An S\***, Kumar A, Malhotra S, Jolly N, Kaur A, Kattoor A, Doukky R, Kalra A,

Vij A

11/2022 Projection of Cancer Incidence and Mortality From 2020 to 2035 in the Korean

Population Aged 20 Years and Older 🛮

J Prev Med Public Health. PMID: 36475318

Hong Y\*, Lee S, Moon S, Sung S, Lim W, Kim K, **An S**, Choi J, Ko KP, Kim I, Lee JE, Park

SK

11/2022	Impact of pulmonary embolism on perioperative outcomes of coronary artery bypass graft ☑ Coron Artery Dis. PMID: 35500089 Park DY*, An S*, Attanasio S, Doukky R, Sawaqed R, Vij A
11/2022	In-hospital prognosis of malignancy-related pulmonary embolism: an analysis of the national inpatient sample 2016-2018   J Thromb Thrombolysis. PMID: 35876942  Park DY*, An S*, Kashoor I, Ezegwu O, Gupta S
11/2022	Impact of cardiac and noncardiac cirrhosis on coronary revascularization outcomes from the National Inpatient Sample, 2016 to 2018 ☑ Proc (Bayl Univ Med Cent) Park DY*, An S*, Warraich MS, Aldeen ZS, Maghari I, Khanal S, Arif AW, Almoghrabi A
10/2022	Modified reverse shock index predicts early outcomes of heart failure with reduced ejection fraction ☑ ESC Heart Fail. PMID: 35775109 Oh GC*, An S*, Lee HY, Cho HJ, Jeon ES, Lee SE, Kim JJ, Kang SM, Hwang KK, Cho MC, Chae SC, Choi DJ, Yoo BS, Kim KH, Park SK, Baek SH
10/2022	Association of metabolic comorbidity with myocardial infarction in individuals with a family history of cardiovascular disease: a prospective cohort study ☑ <i>BMC Public Health. 2022. PMID: 36316766</i> An S*, Moon S, Park SK
10/2022	Readmission rates and risk factors for readmission after transcatheter aortic valve replacement in patients with end-stage renal disease ☑ PLoS One. 2022. PMID: 36264931 Park DY*, An S*, Hanna JM, Wang SY, Cruz-Solbes AS, Kochar A, Lowenstern AM, Forrest JK, Ahmad Y, Cleman M, Damluji AA, Nanna MG
10/2022	Incidence and risk factors of atrial fibrillation and atrial arrhythmias in people living with HIV: a systematic review and meta-analysis ☑ J Interv Card Electrophysiol. PMID: 35610524 Park DY*, An S*, Romero ME, Kaur A, Ravi V, Huang HD, Vij A
09/2022	Shortening the duration of dual antiplatelet therapy after percutaneous coronary intervention for acute coronary syndrome: A systematic review and meta-analysis ☑ Am Heart J. PMID: 35654162 Park DY*, Wang P*, An S, Grimshaw AA, Frampton J, Ohman EM, Rao SV, Nanna MG
07/2022	Impact of end-stage renal disease on in-hospital outcomes of hypertensive emergency from the National Inpatient Sample, 2016 to 2018  Proc (Bayl Univ Med Cent)  Park DY*, An S*, Rodriguez MA, Odeh R, Hammo H, Haque M, Arif AW
07/2022	Myocarditis after COVID-19 mRNA vaccination: A systematic review of case reports and case series ☑ Clin Cardiol. PMID: 35652390 Park DY*, An S*, Kaur A, Malhotra S, Vij A

06/2022	Systematic Review and Network Meta-Analysis Comparing Bifurcation Techniques for Percutaneous Coronary Intervention    Journal of the American Heart Association. PMID: 35723005	
	Park DY*, <b>An S*</b> , Jolly N, Attanasio S, Yadav N, Rao S, Vij A	
06/2022	Binary cutpoint and the combined effect of systolic and diastolic pressure on cardiovascular disease mortality: A community-based cohort study ☐ PLoS One. PMID: 35771898	
	Lee JY*, Hong JH, Lee S, <b>An S</b> , Shin A, Park SK	
05/2022	Comparison of the Prevalence of Cardiometabolic Disorders and Comorbidities in Korea and United States: Analysis of the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey ☑	
	J Korean Med Sci. PMID: 35535376	
	<b>An S*</b> , Ahn C, Jang J, Lee J, Kang D, Lee JK, Park SK	
03/2022	Individualized Biological Age as a Predictor of Disease: Korean Genome and Epidemiology Study (KoGES) Cohort ☑  J Pers Med. PMID: 35330504	
	An S*, Ahn C, Moon S, Sim EJ, Park SK	
03/2022	Effect of weight loss on recurrence of atrial fibrillation after ablative therapy: a systematic review and meta-analysis   J Interv Card Electrophysiol. PMID: 35258752	
	Park DY*, <b>An S</b> , Murthi M, Kattoor AJ, Kaur A, Ravi V, Huang HD, Vij A	
11/2021	Obesity measures at baseline, their trajectories over time, and the incidence of chronic kidney disease: A 14 year cohort study among Korean adults   Nutr Metab Cardiovasc Dis. PMID: 33546946 Zhang HS*, An S, Ahn C, Park SK, Park B	
11/2020	Isoflavone intake on the risk of overall breast cancer and molecular subtypes in women at high risk for hereditary breast cancer ☑  Breast Cancer Res Treat. PMID: 33068197	
	Sim EJ*, Ko KP, Ahn C, Park SM, Surh YJ, <b>An S</b> , Kim SW, Lee MH, Lee JW, Lee JE, Kim KS, Yom CK, Kim HA, Park SK	
08/2019	Long-term Breastfeeding in the Prevention of Allergic Rhinitis: Allergic Rhinitis Cohort Study for Kids (ARCO-Kids Study) ☑ Clin Exp Otorhinolaryngol. PMID: 30992421 Han DH*, Shin JM, An S, Kim JS, Kim DY, Moon S, Kim JS, Cho JS, Kim SW, Kim YH, Roh HJ, Shim WS, Rha KS, Kim SW, Lee SS, Kim DW, Cho KS, Yim HJ, Park SK, Rhee CS	
Patonts		
	Patents	

07/2020	Apparatus and method for predicting chronic kidney disease
Sourth Korea	(Patent Registration No: KR 1020200000929)
06/2019	Device and method for biometric age prediction model generation
South Korea	(Patent Registration No: KR 1020180156873)
06/2019	Apparatus and method for predicting disease risk of metabolic disease
United States	(Patent Publication No: US20190172587A1)

	🤶 Awards
07/2019	<b>Young Investigator Award</b> <i>The Korean Society of Cancer Prevention</i>
07/2018	<b>Young Investigator Award</b> <i>The Korean Society of Cancer Prevention</i>
07/2017	Young Investigator Award

## **Certificates**

The Korean Society of Cancer Prevention

### **SAS Certified Base Programmer for SAS 9**

SAS Global Certification, Certificate Verification No.Y9V19JB12F4Q1T5X

## Canguages

**English** Korean Fluent Native